<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Curated Links on Benjamin Boudreau</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/</link><description>Recent content in Curated Links on Benjamin Boudreau</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><copyright>Copyright © Benjamin Boudreau 2017-2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 08:10:37 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seriousben.com/links/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Against Incident Severities and in Favor of Incident Types</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-11-05-against-incident-severities-and-in-favor-of-incident-types/</link><pubDate>Tue, 05 Nov 2024 08:10:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-11-05-against-incident-severities-and-in-favor-of-incident-types/</guid><description>Comment Ambiguous: Not fully sure. Things look bad, but not fully broken (this is our default type). Internal: Chaos experiments, rollouts, non-customer impacting things, tests. Security: Security incidents have distinct workflows and compliance requirements. Time bomb: Internal, but we need a lot of hands on deck if we don’t want it to get worse. Isolated: One or few customers, over limited components. Major: Key features or important customers are definitely impacted.</description></item><item><title>TBM 318: Why Orgs Become Too Tall</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-31-tbm-318-why-orgs-become-too-tall/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Oct 2024 13:15:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-31-tbm-318-why-orgs-become-too-tall/</guid><description>My thoughts Insightful look at the why behind companies become taller instead of more flat as the company adds employees.
My summary is that these factor play a role:
How much support do people need? Are stakeholders pushing for some roles to signal some company maturity? Was the company structure setup in a way where small teams were created in order to found and grow the teams? Was the role of team management given as a way to give growth opportunity?</description></item><item><title>AI Flame Graphs</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-29-ai-flame-graphs/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 11:20:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-29-ai-flame-graphs/</guid><description>Comment GPU flame graphs. This is great especially as we start relying more and more on AI in the critical path of applications.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Paranoid NixOS on AWS</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-20-paranoid-nixos-on-aws/</link><pubDate>Sun, 20 Oct 2024 17:15:24 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-20-paranoid-nixos-on-aws/</guid><description>My thoughts Creating robust cloud images (ex AWS IAM) from NixOS.
Just amazing. That coupled with https://xeiaso.net/blog/paranoid-nixos-2021-07-18/ provides lots of food for thought and food advice.
Read the article: Paranoid NixOS on AWS</description></item><item><title>The tough reality of being a "glue person"...</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-19-the-tough-reality-of-being-a-glue-person/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Oct 2024 16:11:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-19-the-tough-reality-of-being-a-glue-person/</guid><description>Comment These bullet points feel very close to what I have experienced being a technical leader helping many teams and product lines.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Escaping the Chrome Sandbox Through DevTools</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-17-escaping-the-chrome-sandbox-through-devtools/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Oct 2024 22:47:04 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-17-escaping-the-chrome-sandbox-through-devtools/</guid><description>Comment Amazing step by step investigation done around the Chrome enterprise policies which resulted in two Chrome/Chromium CVE.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Caches in rust</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-03-caches-in-rust/</link><pubDate>Thu, 03 Oct 2024 23:15:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-10-03-caches-in-rust/</guid><description>My thoughts Amazing article about preventing &amp;amp;mut pollution in your rust code for functions that should just be simple getters.
Read the article: Caches in rust</description></item><item><title>The High Reliability Organization Perspective</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-27-the-high-reliability-organization-perspective/</link><pubDate>Fri, 27 Sep 2024 12:28:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-27-the-high-reliability-organization-perspective/</guid><description>My thoughts Great paper highlighting how much intentionality is needed for High Reliability in organizations. I particularly enjoyed the mention of complacency, people and competing priorities factors that come into play.
Excerpt:
Failures are mostly related to the ability of the industry to effectively adapt to, and absorb variations, changes, disturbances, disruptions, and surprises
Rating organizations:
Preparedness/Anticipation: is the organization proactive in picking up on evidence of developing problems versus only reacting after problems become significant?</description></item><item><title>Jevons Paradox</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-25-jevons-paradox/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 Sep 2024 18:03:39 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-25-jevons-paradox/</guid><description>My thoughts In economics, the Jevons paradox (sometimes Jevons effect) occurs when technological progress increases the efficiency with which a resource is used (reducing the amount necessary for any one use), but the falling cost of use induces increases in demand enough that resource use is increased, rather than reduced.
Seen here https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41501146
Read the article: Jevons Paradox</description></item><item><title>Functional table driven tests in go</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-10-functional-table-driven-tests-in-go/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Sep 2024 23:25:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-10-functional-table-driven-tests-in-go/</guid><description>My thoughts Putting a name on this approach is great. I have been using such an approach for a long time and it simplifies tests so much.
Read the article: Functional table driven tests in go</description></item><item><title>Sampling with SQL</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-08-sampling-with-sql/</link><pubDate>Sun, 08 Sep 2024 15:45:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-09-08-sampling-with-sql/</guid><description>My thoughts Sampling with SQL and maths behind the approach
Read the article: Sampling with SQL</description></item><item><title>Minimum Viable CD</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-14-minimum-viable-cd/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Aug 2024 19:26:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-14-minimum-viable-cd/</guid><description>My thoughts Great overview of the minimum CI and CD requirements to get the most out of them.
The most being: increased velocity, quality, engineering culture, developer experience, happiness.
Very similar to https://12factor.net/
Here are some highlights.
for CD:
All feature work stops when the pipeline is red. Artifacts created by the pipeline always meet the organization’s definition of deployable. (Which makes me think of the definition of done of Scrum) Rollback on-demand For CI:</description></item><item><title>Beware the dopamine cartel</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-10-beware-the-dopamine-cartel/</link><pubDate>Sat, 10 Aug 2024 14:15:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-10-beware-the-dopamine-cartel/</guid><description>My thoughts Analysis of today&amp;rsquo;s addictions in terms of dopamine and some small tips.
Read the article: Beware the dopamine cartel</description></item><item><title>How to be concise</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-09-how-to-be-concise/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Aug 2024 15:01:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-09-how-to-be-concise/</guid><description>My thoughts Great thoughts on what it means to be concise and some tips.
Read the article: How to be concise</description></item><item><title>BM25</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-07-bm25/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:28:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-07-bm25/</guid><description>My thoughts from simonw on HN:
BM25 is similar to TF/IDF. In both cases, the key idea is to consider statistics of the overall corpus as part of relevance calculations. If the user searches for &amp;ldquo;charities in new orleans&amp;rdquo; in a corpus where &amp;ldquo;new orleans&amp;rdquo; is only represented in a few documents, those should clearly rank highly. If the corpus has &amp;ldquo;new orleans&amp;rdquo; in almost every document then the term &amp;ldquo;charity&amp;rdquo; is more important.</description></item><item><title>Implementing faceted search with Django and PostgreSQL</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-07-implementing-faceted-search-with-django-and-postgresql/</link><pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 11:20:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-07-implementing-faceted-search-with-django-and-postgresql/</guid><description>My thoughts Great detailed look at implementing faceted search using postgres.
This might alleviate the fact that postgres full text search does not support BM25.
more infor on postgres search in https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=41173288
Read the article: Implementing faceted search with Django and PostgreSQL</description></item><item><title>Inspiration &amp; plans for (agile) retrospectives</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-01-inspiration-and-plans-for-agile-retrospectives/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Aug 2024 17:41:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-08-01-inspiration-and-plans-for-agile-retrospectives/</guid><description>My thoughts Lots of great scenarios/templates for their four parts of a retrospective:
set the stage: Time to &amp;ldquo;arrive&amp;rdquo;, get into the right mood and focus on the goal.
Gather Data: Help everyone remember and create a shared pool of information.
Generate Insights: Why did things happen this way? Any patterns? See the big picture.
Close the retro: How could the retrospectives improve?</description></item><item><title>Categories of leadership on technical teams</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-07-31-categories-of-leadership-on-technical-teams/</link><pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 00:38:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-07-31-categories-of-leadership-on-technical-teams/</guid><description>My thoughts interesting article identifying the different aspects of a team requiring leadership and provide example archetype of how team split up these leadership aspects between leaders.
Read the article: Categories of leadership on technical teams</description></item><item><title>A write-ahead log is not a universal part of durability</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-07-01-a-write-ahead-log-is-not-a-universal-part-of-durability/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jul 2024 23:05:08 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-07-01-a-write-ahead-log-is-not-a-universal-part-of-durability/</guid><description>Comment Interesting look at what WAL is and isn&amp;rsquo;t. HN has some good comments: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40844825
Read more</description></item><item><title>Instead of “auth”, we should say “permissions” and “login”</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-05-27-instead-of-auth-we-should-say-permissions-and-login/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 May 2024 21:50:22 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-05-27-instead-of-auth-we-should-say-permissions-and-login/</guid><description>Comment Sharing for aeonik&amp;rsquo;s comment on HN:
&amp;ldquo;Authorize&amp;rdquo; and &amp;ldquo;Authenticate&amp;rdquo; are excellent words. They go back to medieval times and haven&amp;rsquo;t changed meaning too much.
Everybody knows what an &amp;ldquo;authority&amp;rdquo; is. It means they have power or capability.
Everybody knows what authentic means. Something that is proven to be genuine.
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=40491480
Read more</description></item><item><title>Second-system effect</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-27-second-system-effect/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Mar 2024 16:10:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-27-second-system-effect/</guid><description>My thoughts The second-system effect or second-system syndrome is the tendency of small, elegant, and successful systems to be succeeded by over-engineered, bloated systems, due to inflated expectations and overconfidence.
From the &amp;ldquo;The Mythical Man-Month&amp;rdquo;. Useful syndrome to keep in mind when &amp;ldquo;re-writing&amp;rdquo; a working system. The complexity of having parity and adding new capabilities is often underestimated.
Read the article: Second-system effect</description></item><item><title>An incomplete list of skills senior engineers need, beyond coding</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-20-an-incomplete-list-of-skills-senior-engineers-need-beyond-coding/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 15:45:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-20-an-incomplete-list-of-skills-senior-engineers-need-beyond-coding/</guid><description>My thoughts Really down to earth list by Camille Fournier.
My highlights:
How to find interesting work on your own, instead of waiting for someone to bring it to you How to get information about what’s really happening (how to gossip, how to network) How to repeat yourself enough that people start to listen How to teach another engineer to care about that thing you really care about (operations, correctness, testing, code quality, performance, simplicity, etc) How to listen to other engineers’ ideas without feeling threatened How to lead a project even though you don’t manage any of the people working on the project Read the article: An incomplete list of skills senior engineers need, beyond coding</description></item><item><title>Making very intentional career choices</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-16-making-very-intentional-career-choices/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 23:51:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-16-making-very-intentional-career-choices/</guid><description>My thoughts I think the four factors described make a lot of sense:
what kind of life you want to create your superpowers what type of work energizes you what type of people you love working with I am a huge fan of intentionality. What is described is being able to recognize peer/cultural/social pressure in order to focus our what type of environment works for you. That aspect brings another layer to intentionality by also addressing our own bias and improving our decision making.</description></item><item><title>Getting Things Done In A Chaotic Environment</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-16-getting-things-done-in-a-chaotic-environment/</link><pubDate>Sat, 16 Mar 2024 23:31:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-16-getting-things-done-in-a-chaotic-environment/</guid><description>My thoughts One of the first things my CEO told me is that things move fast, so you have to get things done as completely as possible and move on to the next thing.
I feel this means completely finish whatever urgent and non important tasks that come up as quickly as possible so that you can get back to the important tasks.
I also love the expression: &amp;ldquo;The number one cause of a page or an incident is not solving the last page or incident&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>TBM 274: How Capable Leaders Navigate Uncertainty and Ambiguity</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-08-tbm-274-how-capable-leaders-navigate-uncertainty-and-ambiguity/</link><pubDate>Fri, 08 Mar 2024 19:51:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-08-tbm-274-how-capable-leaders-navigate-uncertainty-and-ambiguity/</guid><description>Comment Amazing post containing data about what feels like a very humane / empathetic leadership approach to navigating unknown / uncertainty.
It is putting complex concepts into easily understandable words. It really helps turn approaches I have observed and value a lot into into an actionable list.
Really a treasure chest of tips.
Accept We Are Part of the Problem Encourage New Interaction Patterns Patient Divergence Identify Plausible Contributors / Multiple &amp;ldquo;Causes&amp;rdquo; Power of the Present Blend Diverse Perspectives Patience and Self-Repair Anticipate Effects Curiosity and Light Touch Both/And Intervene Safely Abduction and Intuition Accept Diverse Strengths and Skills Collaboratively Sense and Shape Coherence vs.</description></item><item><title>Parkinson's law, Work complicates to fill the available time</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-06-parkinsons-law-work-complicates-to-fill-the-available-time/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Mar 2024 22:08:36 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-03-06-parkinsons-law-work-complicates-to-fill-the-available-time/</guid><description>My thoughts I was reminded of this law from https://theengineeringmanager.substack.com/p/parkinsons-law-its-real-so-use-it
James wrote:
without tight time constraints, the scope of a team&amp;rsquo;s project will expand to fill the time available.
I have seen so many different teams falling in that trap: Teams tackling every edge cases even if not required by any users, newly found edge cases requiring a rewrite of a feature not yet shipped, teams burning the midnight oil on an ever expanding project scope&amp;hellip;</description></item><item><title>How I write HTTP services in Go after 13 years</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-02-19-how-i-write-http-services-in-go-after-13-years/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Feb 2024 20:51:31 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-02-19-how-i-write-http-services-in-go-after-13-years/</guid><description>My thoughts Interesting take on setting up an HTTP service. They mention that using grpc or different protocols might require to adjust the structure. I would be curious to get their take on a service supporting grpc and HTTP to help me revisit older decisions.
The signal.NotifyContext(ctx, os.Interrupt) approach to cancel context on interrupt is really an improvement over starting a goroutine and using Notify with a channel.
Best advice is to not use global scope to allow parallel testing without sporadic failures.</description></item><item><title>TBM 269: Three Organizational Design Principles</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-02-17-tbm-269-three-organizational-design-principles/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Feb 2024 23:01:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-02-17-tbm-269-three-organizational-design-principles/</guid><description>Comment I really like the final four points:
Encapsulate complexity to your advantage. Make sure people can collaborate closely when the work requires it.
Establish clear transactional relationships and interfaces between groups that don&amp;rsquo;t require intensive collaboration. Good walls make good neighbors.
Make sure that managers and leaders maintain relationships that mimic the relationships required by the people doing the work.
If possible, genuinely simplify our business processes—true simplification, not just in name.</description></item><item><title>Macaroons Escalated Quickly</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-02-01-macaroons-escalated-quickly/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Feb 2024 04:18:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-02-01-macaroons-escalated-quickly/</guid><description>Comment Super interesting approach that is very pragmatic and very similar to the aws access keys of AWS but much more powerful.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Questionable Advice: “My boss says we don’t need any engineering managers. Is he right?”</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-01-21-questionable-advice-my-boss-says-we-dont-need-any-engineering-managers-is-he-right/</link><pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 01:12:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2024-01-21-questionable-advice-my-boss-says-we-dont-need-any-engineering-managers-is-he-right/</guid><description>Comment Amazing take explaining why managers are needed.
I really like the graph theory image where without managers, each engineer need to maintain a relationship with a lot of engineers instead of focusing on outcomes.
Read more</description></item><item><title>The three email addresses of OpenID Connect (OIDC) in practice</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-12-17-the-three-email-addresses-of-openid-connect-oidc-in-practice/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 Dec 2023 05:12:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-12-17-the-three-email-addresses-of-openid-connect-oidc-in-practice/</guid><description>Comment Linking the validity of email domains to their OIDC provider domain is something I had never heard before.
But the whole SSO domain ownership is full of interesting security implications.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Can't Be Fucked: Underrated Cause of Tech Debt</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-10-12-cant-be-fucked-underrated-cause-of-tech-debt/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 23:37:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-10-12-cant-be-fucked-underrated-cause-of-tech-debt/</guid><description>Comment Funny (real?) take on another cause for tech debt.
The HN comments are amazing https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37859311 but sometimes a little depressing.
Read more</description></item><item><title>NIST Elliptic Curves Seeds Bounty</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-10-06-nist-elliptic-curves-seeds-bounty/</link><pubDate>Fri, 06 Oct 2023 10:27:18 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-10-06-nist-elliptic-curves-seeds-bounty/</guid><description>Comment Amazing story of the NIST curves.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Insomnium – Local, privacy-focused fork of Insomnia API client</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-09-30-insomnium-local-privacy-focused-fork-of-insomnia-api-client/</link><pubDate>Sat, 30 Sep 2023 00:23:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-09-30-insomnium-local-privacy-focused-fork-of-insomnia-api-client/</guid><description>Comment Insomnia require an account now. HN has alternatives https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37708582
Read more</description></item><item><title>Choose Postgres queue technology</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-09-25-choose-postgres-queue-technology/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Sep 2023 00:08:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-09-25-choose-postgres-queue-technology/</guid><description>Comment Great points about tech tradeoffs and pragmatism.
The SELECT FOR UPDATE SKIP LOCK approach is really interesting.
HN has more good examples and a list of tradeoffs. https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37636841
Read more</description></item><item><title>Blueprint for a distributed multi-region IAM with Go and CockroachDB</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-08-08-blueprint-for-a-distributed-multi-region-iam-with-go-and-cockroachdb/</link><pubDate>Tue, 08 Aug 2023 23:20:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-08-08-blueprint-for-a-distributed-multi-region-iam-with-go-and-cockroachdb/</guid><description>Comment Amazing blog post on having a global identity service and all the concerns to look into.
It also mentions the decision that Ory made to build their cloud in that way.
Lots of really good callouts like disaster recovery, latency, consistency, and an approach to also have data residency in a global service.
HN for other people&amp;rsquo;s take on the approach https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=37048409
Read more</description></item><item><title>JavaScript Gom Jabbar</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-07-03-javascript-gom-jabbar/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Jul 2023 10:55:34 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-07-03-javascript-gom-jabbar/</guid><description>Comment Deep dive into node&amp;rsquo;s package.json and all the history behind it.
Read more</description></item><item><title>I think Zig is hard but worth it</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-06-01-i-think-zig-is-hard-but-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 22:58:37 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-06-01-i-think-zig-is-hard-but-worth-it/</guid><description>Comment Interesting look at zig. Interesting HN comments https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36149462
Read more</description></item><item><title>Lost John Coltrane recording, from experimental phase with Eric Dolphy, emerges</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-06-01-lost-john-coltrane-recording-from-experimental-phase-with-eric-dolphy-emerges/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Jun 2023 09:35:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-06-01-lost-john-coltrane-recording-from-experimental-phase-with-eric-dolphy-emerges/</guid><description>Comment Great comments on HN https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=36146905
Read more</description></item><item><title>Architects, Anti-Patterns, and Organizational Fuckery</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-03-09-architects-anti-patterns-and-organizational-fuckery/</link><pubDate>Thu, 09 Mar 2023 12:38:11 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-03-09-architects-anti-patterns-and-organizational-fuckery/</guid><description>Comment Amazing blog posts. Lots of exploration in the different architect archetypes, staff and principal engineers.
The title is a bit strong. But the post itself takes a more nuanced approach.
I really enjoyed it.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Let It Fail</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-03-02-let-it-fail/</link><pubDate>Thu, 02 Mar 2023 12:26:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-03-02-let-it-fail/</guid><description>Comment Interesting take on changing systems without relying on heroism and without trying to get prioritized project that don&amp;rsquo;t seem to have business value. Letting things fail (in a controlled way) can help align and change the systems. Being proactive is not always the best approach.
Things did indeed break. But as they did something else happened: our product team began to see the legacy system would not support the business goals and they went from somewhat passive admirers of the theory to active evangelists of the platform work.</description></item><item><title>“Yes, if”: Iterating on our RFC Process</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-02-27-yes-if-iterating-on-our-rfc-process/</link><pubDate>Mon, 27 Feb 2023 12:27:06 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-02-27-yes-if-iterating-on-our-rfc-process/</guid><description>Comment Interesting take on a RFC process. At Hashi, RFCs are used to provide teams with more de decision making powers as opposed to centralizing reviewing and decision to a council. Trade-offs.
HN comments provide other opinions: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34946844
Read more</description></item><item><title>SQL should be the default choice for data engineering pipelines</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-01-31-sql-should-be-the-default-choice-for-data-engineering-pipelines/</link><pubDate>Tue, 31 Jan 2023 12:49:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-01-31-sql-should-be-the-default-choice-for-data-engineering-pipelines/</guid><description>Comment Interesting take into data pipelines.
Read more</description></item><item><title>We invested 10% to pay back tech debt</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-01-16-we-invested-10-to-pay-back-tech-debt/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Jan 2023 13:23:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2023-01-16-we-invested-10-to-pay-back-tech-debt/</guid><description>Comment From HN (https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34394351):
If you assign a block of time to quality, you risk people taking that as an excuse to not focus on quality outside that block.
I feel like this has been my worry and experience for a while. Good teams I have been at shipped quality by default. They would not require bug blitz or similar. Except for well defined area of complexity or integration with another team.</description></item><item><title>What happens when babies are left to cry it out?</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-12-30-what-happens-when-babies-are-left-to-cry-it-out/</link><pubDate>Fri, 30 Dec 2022 01:54:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-12-30-what-happens-when-babies-are-left-to-cry-it-out/</guid><description>Comment Interesting view of the studies done in that domain. Summary and opinions available on HN https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=34173006
Read more</description></item><item><title>Police, prosecutors used junk science to decide 911 callers were liars</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-12-29-police-prosecutors-used-junk-science-to-decide-911-callers-were-liars/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Dec 2022 01:40:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-12-29-police-prosecutors-used-junk-science-to-decide-911-callers-were-liars/</guid><description>Comment Great research, sad reality
Read more</description></item><item><title>How are you doing?</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-12-14-how-are-you-doing/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Dec 2022 12:23:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-12-14-how-are-you-doing/</guid><description>Comment Trigger warning: some mention of very negative thoughts.
I thought this exercise was great. Being able to map feelings, colors, how it impacts your body.
Self-awareness and so difficult for with all the stimuli we face everyday.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Salary Transparency</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-25-salary-transparency/</link><pubDate>Tue, 25 Oct 2022 03:32:54 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-25-salary-transparency/</guid><description>Comment This is something I might consider. My own salary page.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Why Some Feedback Hurts (and What To Do About It)</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-07-why-some-feedback-hurts-and-what-to-do-about-it/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 12:20:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-07-why-some-feedback-hurts-and-what-to-do-about-it/</guid><description>Comment Giving feedback is difficult. Getting hurtful feedback is so difficult to digest.
I really like this part about it being ok to ignore feedback when it is not aligned with your goals. But to make sure to emphatize with the feedback.
Changes that will be too difficult or costly to undertake: By no means should you feel compelled to accede to all of the hurtful feedback you receive. Some of the changes people are asking for will either impose an intolerable burden on you or will prevent you from accomplishing your goals as a leader.</description></item><item><title>The Importance of Shared Narrative</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-07-the-importance-of-shared-narrative/</link><pubDate>Fri, 07 Oct 2022 12:16:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-07-the-importance-of-shared-narrative/</guid><description>Comment Storytelling as a leadership tool. I love it.
involve getting out of your comfort zone and dealing with vulnerability and even embarrassment. (If you never feel these feelings, you&amp;rsquo;re playing it safe and being too cautious.)
Read more</description></item><item><title>Build Your Career on Dirty Work</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-04-build-your-career-on-dirty-work/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 12:25:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-04-build-your-career-on-dirty-work/</guid><description>Comment Interesting take on making an impact.
Read more</description></item><item><title>We Burned Down Players’ Houses in Ultima Online</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-04-we-burned-down-players-houses-in-ultima-online/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 03:05:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-10-04-we-burned-down-players-houses-in-ultima-online/</guid><description>Comment Wow amazing story of fraud management in onenofnthe first MMO game.
Read more</description></item><item><title>age and Authenticated Encryption</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-29-age-and-authenticated-encryption/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 23:49:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-29-age-and-authenticated-encryption/</guid><description>Comment Amazing post with so many examples and details around encryption and authentication.
Very well written and so informative.
Read more</description></item><item><title>The Disappearing Art of Maintenance</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-27-the-disappearing-art-of-maintenance/</link><pubDate>Tue, 27 Sep 2022 22:43:14 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-27-the-disappearing-art-of-maintenance/</guid><description>Comment Interesting that maintenance issues in non tech domains are very similar to maintenance and tech debt management in tech.
Coming from the human nature: short term gains are often more prioritized over greater long term gains.
From HN:
When I studied Chinese in primary school, there was one ancient text that spoke about a discussion between a king and a famous doctor. The doctor explained that his brother was superior than him in the medical science but no one heard about him because he could always treat small illnesses before then evolved into terminal ones, so people said, &amp;ldquo;Oh he is a fine doctor, but he only treats minor illnesses&amp;rdquo;.</description></item><item><title>Ask HN: Name 3-5 books that had the most impact on your career and knowledge?</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-19-ask-hn-name-3-5-books-that-had-the-most-impact-on-your-career-and-knowledge/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 23:14:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-19-ask-hn-name-3-5-books-that-had-the-most-impact-on-your-career-and-knowledge/</guid><description>Comment Great list of books
Read more</description></item><item><title>There is no “software supply chain”</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-19-there-is-no-software-supply-chain/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Sep 2022 22:59:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-19-there-is-no-software-supply-chain/</guid><description>Comment Interesting takes on the software supply chain.
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32902938
In HN a comment is very interesting:
This will sound pretty harsh, but if your company chooses to use open source code that does not have capable, paid, full time professionals reviewing it for security and quality, then your company is signing up for that responsibility. If you make no reasonable attempt at vetting your supply chain and harm comes to users as a result, then IMO you should be liable for negligence just like a restaurant serving food with poisonous ingredients.</description></item><item><title>Using WebTransport</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-17-using-webtransport/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Sep 2022 13:22:52 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-17-using-webtransport/</guid><description>Comment My understanding: UDP websockets. Pretty interesting tech.
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32867644
Read more</description></item><item><title>Working Iteratively</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-16-working-iteratively/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 Sep 2022 01:46:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-16-working-iteratively/</guid><description>Comment Great article about working iteratively
Read more</description></item><item><title>How to help crying infants sleep. Study suggests a two-part path: “walk-to-sit” [pdf]</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-15-how-to-help-crying-infants-sleep-study-suggests-a-two-part-path-walk-to-sit-pdf/</link><pubDate>Thu, 15 Sep 2022 08:53:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-15-how-to-help-crying-infants-sleep-study-suggests-a-two-part-path-walk-to-sit-pdf/</guid><description>Comment Research paper about infant sleep. Hacker news comments are also very good with lots of tips: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32845229
(I am reviewing this while my 1yo has decided to not go back to sleep. Been awake for 3 hour and it is 5am)
Read more</description></item><item><title>Senior Engineers Are Living in the Future</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-14-senior-engineers-are-living-in-the-future/</link><pubDate>Wed, 14 Sep 2022 02:28:53 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-14-senior-engineers-are-living-in-the-future/</guid><description>Comment Great explanation of how senior engineers got to where they are and the feedback loop giving them all informations to seem like they are from the future.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Ask HN: Do you use foreign keys in relational databases?</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-09-ask-hn-do-you-use-foreign-keys-in-relational-databases/</link><pubDate>Fri, 09 Sep 2022 00:39:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-09-ask-hn-do-you-use-foreign-keys-in-relational-databases/</guid><description>Comment Most common opinion seems to be to treat our database as precious and therefore protect its integrity.
Read more</description></item><item><title>TBM 28/52: First Focus. Then Simplify</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-01-tbm-28-52-first-focus-then-simplify/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 13:29:40 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-01-tbm-28-52-first-focus-then-simplify/</guid><description>Comment The definition of focusing and simplifying is so great. Focusing on key areas that have the biggest impact helps keeping things moving. It feels simpler, but it does not make the problem simpler.
A complex problem cannot be simplified.
If you can simplify it, then it isn’t a complex problem.
You may choose to focus energy on a key leverage point, or establish one or more enabling constraints. To make progress, you may choose to selectively ignore things, blur your vision, or think in broad strokes.</description></item><item><title>Falsehoods programmers believe about email</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-01-falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-email/</link><pubDate>Thu, 01 Sep 2022 11:06:56 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-09-01-falsehoods-programmers-believe-about-email/</guid><description>Comment Great list. HN comments are also good https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32671959
Read more</description></item><item><title>Stick to Tinkering</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-30-stick-to-tinkering/</link><pubDate>Tue, 30 Aug 2022 22:18:49 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-30-stick-to-tinkering/</guid><description>Comment Really good perspective on tinkering.
So, my advice to young developers, please stick to tinkering whenever possible. You won’t learn much reading the User Manual of your TV, only when you actually tinker with it you become a master. Tinkering will help you connect some dots in your brain that can’t be connected otherwise. It increases your “courage”, widens your perspective, and teach you how to fearlessly get out some tough situations.</description></item><item><title>Research Paper Simple Template</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-24-research-paper-simple-template/</link><pubDate>Wed, 24 Aug 2022 23:35:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-24-research-paper-simple-template/</guid><description>Comment Using this to format blog posts also seems like a good idea.
Read more</description></item><item><title>RFC 9293: Transmission Control Protocol (TCP)</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-19-rfc-9293-transmission-control-protocol-tcp/</link><pubDate>Fri, 19 Aug 2022 18:59:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-19-rfc-9293-transmission-control-protocol-tcp/</guid><description>Comment TCP RFC bringing all the TCP RFCs under one RFC. Really good way to understand what TCP is about.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Communicating Effectively As A Tech Lead</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-17-communicating-effectively-as-a-tech-lead/</link><pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 12:33:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-17-communicating-effectively-as-a-tech-lead/</guid><description>Comment Interesting list of tips to better communicate. Very actionable list.
Read more</description></item><item><title>The secret to getting to the Staff+ level? Leverage.</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-11-the-secret-to-getting-to-the-staff-level-leverage/</link><pubDate>Thu, 11 Aug 2022 15:12:15 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-08-11-the-secret-to-getting-to-the-staff-level-leverage/</guid><description>Comment Very interesting take on Staff level and IC&amp;rsquo;s career path.
Camille mentions it is about leverage. Different types of leverage: interpersonal, execution, strategic, and expert.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Finishing what you start makes teams more productive and predictable</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-27-finishing-what-you-start-makes-teams-more-productive-and-predictable/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 11:55:41 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-27-finishing-what-you-start-makes-teams-more-productive-and-predictable/</guid><description>Comment Great article with visuals.
Predictability has always been very important in my eyes. I really like that take on it: finishing what you start.
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32220514
Read more</description></item><item><title>How to Stop Procrastinating on Your Goals by Using the “Seinfeld Strategy”</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-27-how-to-stop-procrastinating-on-your-goals-by-using-the-seinfeld-strategy/</link><pubDate>Wed, 27 Jul 2022 11:47:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-27-how-to-stop-procrastinating-on-your-goals-by-using-the-seinfeld-strategy/</guid><description>Comment Interesting take on procrastination. I really really like the first HN comment on springboard procastination.
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32245545
Read more</description></item><item><title>Ask HN: What are some 'cool' but obscure data structures you know about?</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-22-ask-hn-what-are-some-cool-but-obscure-data-structures-you-know-about/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Jul 2022 02:07:58 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-22-ask-hn-what-are-some-cool-but-obscure-data-structures-you-know-about/</guid><description>Comment Really interesting thread on leveraging data structures for common problems
Read more</description></item><item><title>Don’t make the plan better. Make it shorter: why long term plans don’t work</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-21-dont-make-the-plan-better-make-it-shorter-why-long-term-plans-dont-work/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Jul 2022 00:43:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-21-dont-make-the-plan-better-make-it-shorter-why-long-term-plans-dont-work/</guid><description>Comment Lots of different opinions in HN https://lucasfcosta.com/2022/07/15/long-term-plans-dont-work.html
Read more</description></item><item><title>Soft Deletion Probably Isn't Worth It</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-19-soft-deletion-probably-isnt-worth-it/</link><pubDate>Tue, 19 Jul 2022 23:34:28 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-19-soft-deletion-probably-isnt-worth-it/</guid><description>Comment Great summary of the soft deletion approach and interesting alternative.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Code in database vs. code in application</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-10-code-in-database-vs-code-in-application/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Jul 2022 22:24:30 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-10-code-in-database-vs-code-in-application/</guid><description>Comment Interesting look at application logic in databases
Read more</description></item><item><title>SOC2: The screenshots will continue until security improves</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-07-soc2-the-screenshots-will-continue-until-security-improves/</link><pubDate>Thu, 07 Jul 2022 22:06:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-07-soc2-the-screenshots-will-continue-until-security-improves/</guid><description>Comment Amazing opinionated piece on getting SOC2 compliance.
https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=32018066
Read more</description></item><item><title>Learn TLA+</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-02-learn-tla/</link><pubDate>Sat, 02 Jul 2022 11:25:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-07-02-learn-tla/</guid><description>Comment Great resource. HN comments at https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31952643 also have great insights and links.
Read more</description></item><item><title>New UUID Formats from IETF</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-06-12-new-uuid-formats-from-ietf/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jun 2022 19:38:02 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-06-12-new-uuid-formats-from-ietf/</guid><description>Comment Defining UUID version 6, 7 and 8. To improve DB data locality and address issues that caused many different systems to create their own ID like ULID and ObjectID.
Read more</description></item><item><title>The Two Generals Problem</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-25-the-two-generals-problem/</link><pubDate>Wed, 25 May 2022 11:39:32 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-25-the-two-generals-problem/</guid><description>Comment Amazing explanation of distributed system synchronization.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Why billing systems are a nightmare for engineers</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-18-why-billing-systems-are-a-nightmare-for-engineers/</link><pubDate>Wed, 18 May 2022 17:47:55 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-18-why-billing-systems-are-a-nightmare-for-engineers/</guid><description>Comment Interesting view of billing systems https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=31424450
Read more</description></item><item><title>Heroku: Core Impact</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-16-heroku-core-impact/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 May 2022 21:02:27 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-16-heroku-core-impact/</guid><description>Comment Great post. The concept of erosion resistance was new to me.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Show HN: Mitmproxy2swagger – Automagically reverse-engineer REST APIs</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-12-show-hn-mitmproxy2swagger-automagically-reverse-engineer-rest-apis/</link><pubDate>Thu, 12 May 2022 20:35:16 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-05-12-show-hn-mitmproxy2swagger-automagically-reverse-engineer-rest-apis/</guid><description>Comment Amazing way to reverse engineer APIs.
Read more</description></item><item><title>A list of new(ish) command line tools</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-15-a-list-of-new-ish-command-line-tools/</link><pubDate>Fri, 15 Apr 2022 23:25:23 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-15-a-list-of-new-ish-command-line-tools/</guid><description>Comment Amazing list
Read more</description></item><item><title>The Personal Security Checklist</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-04-the-personal-security-checklist/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Apr 2022 14:00:57 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-04-the-personal-security-checklist/</guid><description>Comment Amazing personal privacy list
Read more</description></item><item><title>Flexible &amp; Correct Identity Access Control Models</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-03-flexible-and-correct-identity-access-control-models/</link><pubDate>Sun, 03 Apr 2022 14:04:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-03-flexible-and-correct-identity-access-control-models/</guid><description>Comment SpiceDB / Zanzibar is an amazing way to configure IAM.
Read more</description></item><item><title>How I operated as a Staff engineer at Heroku (2020)</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-01-how-i-operated-as-a-staff-engineer-at-heroku-2020/</link><pubDate>Fri, 01 Apr 2022 12:31:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-04-01-how-i-operated-as-a-staff-engineer-at-heroku-2020/</guid><description>Comment Great insights. The HN comments are also useful: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=30870148
Read more</description></item><item><title>Why you should maybe not work so hard</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-29-why-you-should-maybe-not-work-so-hard/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Mar 2022 13:42:03 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-29-why-you-should-maybe-not-work-so-hard/</guid><description>Comment Interesting view. The HN comments are very insightful: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=30829243
Read more</description></item><item><title>Implementing a toy version of TLS 1.3</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-25-implementing-a-toy-version-of-tls-1-3/</link><pubDate>Fri, 25 Mar 2022 02:11:05 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-25-implementing-a-toy-version-of-tls-1-3/</guid><description>Comment Amazingly interesting!!!
Read more</description></item><item><title>The Code Review Pyramid</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-15-the-code-review-pyramid/</link><pubDate>Tue, 15 Mar 2022 22:03:42 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-15-the-code-review-pyramid/</guid><description>Comment This pyramid of where to spend most time during reviews is amazing.
I like the visual of it and I like how time to change in the future (or what I would call time to revert) is the main metric used.
Very pragmatic!
Read more</description></item><item><title>A non-standard book list for software developers</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-13-a-non-standard-book-list-for-software-developers/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Mar 2022 02:41:29 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-13-a-non-standard-book-list-for-software-developers/</guid><description>Comment Very non-standard list of books. The HN thread has also good recommendations https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=30651273
Read more</description></item><item><title>The perils of the “real” client IP</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-06-the-perils-of-the-real-client-ip/</link><pubDate>Sun, 06 Mar 2022 02:43:07 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-03-06-the-perils-of-the-real-client-ip/</guid><description>Comment Amazing look at the security implications of the x-forwarded-for and similar headers.
Read more</description></item><item><title>What TPMs Do and What Software Engineers Can Learn From Them</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-19-what-tpms-do-and-what-software-engineers-can-learn-from-them/</link><pubDate>Sat, 19 Feb 2022 10:56:20 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-19-what-tpms-do-and-what-software-engineers-can-learn-from-them/</guid><description>Comment Great read with lots of amazing information.
The section &amp;ldquo;Working with TPMs as engineers and EMs&amp;rdquo; is particularly interesting.
Don’t forget what’s in it for you as an engineering manager or engineer, in working with a TPM. By being able to work with a TPM, you have someone who worries – and takes care of – the project being shipped across multiple teams. This means you can spend more time on your own work and less time worrying about other teams.</description></item><item><title>Balancing Safety and Velocity in CI/CD at Slack</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-18-balancing-safety-and-velocity-in-ci-cd-at-slack/</link><pubDate>Fri, 18 Feb 2022 11:06:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-18-balancing-safety-and-velocity-in-ci-cd-at-slack/</guid><description>Comment Very interesting take on end-to-end tests
Read more</description></item><item><title>Don't defer Close() on writable files</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-13-dont-defer-close-on-writable-files/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 20:13:44 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-13-dont-defer-close-on-writable-files/</guid><description>Comment Great post. And the two updates are also very great.
Read more</description></item><item><title>Putting Ideas into Words</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-13-putting-ideas-into-words/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 14:30:25 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-13-putting-ideas-into-words/</guid><description>Comment Learning when teaching and writing.
It is so very true. When I sit to write about something, I always realize how big the topic really is.
I discover different opinions, different approaches, tradeoffs that I had been making without being intentional about it, &amp;hellip;
There is always more to learn!
Read more</description></item><item><title>Testing Distributed Systems</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-13-testing-distributed-systems/</link><pubDate>Sun, 13 Feb 2022 02:55:13 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-13-testing-distributed-systems/</guid><description>Comment Amazing list of resources
Read more</description></item><item><title>Stop Writing Great Runbooks</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-12-stop-writing-great-runbooks/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 18:29:21 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-12-stop-writing-great-runbooks/</guid><description>Comment Strong opinions but valuable insight.
The problem is that runbooks are documented failure: failure to fix things properly, failure to automate solutions, failure to prioritize. Furthermore, runbooks are often praised for being clear and easy to use. In reality, the clearer and easier a runbook is to execute, the more unforgivable it is that you haven’t automated the solution.
The Catch-22 Of Runbooks is Any runbook that is easy to execute should not exist.</description></item><item><title>Modern public TLS is a quite different thing than it used to be</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-10-modern-public-tls-is-a-quite-different-thing-than-it-used-to-be/</link><pubDate>Thu, 10 Feb 2022 13:37:33 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-10-modern-public-tls-is-a-quite-different-thing-than-it-used-to-be/</guid><description>Comment Tons of insights into TLS
Read more</description></item><item><title>Career advice nobody gave me: Never ignore a recruiter</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-02-career-advice-nobody-gave-me-never-ignore-a-recruiter/</link><pubDate>Wed, 02 Feb 2022 13:10:59 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-02-02-career-advice-nobody-gave-me-never-ignore-a-recruiter/</guid><description>Comment Interesting take on handling recruiters reaching out.
Other interesting inputs in the HN thread: https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=30163676
Read more</description></item><item><title>Tips for a Healthier Postgres Database</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-01-09-tips-for-a-healthier-postgres-database/</link><pubDate>Sun, 09 Jan 2022 16:20:51 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/2022-01-09-tips-for-a-healthier-postgres-database/</guid><description>Comment Interesting small numbers of tips and accompanying HN post (https://news.ycombinator.com/item?id=29858083)
Read more</description></item><item><title>Implementing a random by ID flag type</title><link>https://seriousben.com/links/implementing-a-random-by-id-flag-type/</link><pubDate>Sun, 28 Nov 2021 01:39:47 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/links/implementing-a-random-by-id-flag-type/</guid><description>Comment Very useful way to deterministically rolling out features.
Read more</description></item></channel></rss>