<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Benjamin Boudreau</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Benjamin Boudreau</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en</language><copyright>Copyright © Benjamin Boudreau 2017-2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:00:00 -0400</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://seriousben.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Being Nice to Reviewers: Splitting Large PRs in the AI Era</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/2025-07-splitting-large-prs-ai-era/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Jul 2025 10:00:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/2025-07-splitting-large-prs-ai-era/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;strong&gt;Note&lt;/strong&gt;: This post was written with the assistance of an LLM (Claude), which seemed fitting given the topic. The ideas, experiences, and approach described are my own, but AI helped structure the writing and generate the example script—much like how AI can help us split large PRs while human judgment guides the strategy.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AI tools are making us incredibly productive at writing code. They are also making our pull requests massive. What used to be a 5-file feature now easily becomes 30+ files spanning database migrations, API endpoints, frontend components, tests, and configuration changes. This increased productivity is amazing, but it has created a new problem: we are overwhelming our reviewers.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Patch Coverage</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/2022-02-patch-coverage/</link><pubDate>Sat, 12 Feb 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/2022-02-patch-coverage/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Code Coverage as a way to track code quality has existed for as long as code
exists. For that same amount of time, different schools of thought have debated
on how best to leverage coverage to help drive quality. For example, the
concept of &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Modified_condition/decision_coverage" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Modified condition/decision
coverage&lt;/a&gt;

which defines a criterion used in avionics, in automotive, and in lots of
safety-critical systems has been referred to in standards &lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/DO-178B" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;created in
1992&lt;/a&gt;
.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But this post is not exploring the philosophical aspects of code coverage. It
is about one metric we get with coverage: patch code coverage.
We&amp;rsquo;ll explore what it is and how it can be used to write better code, how it
can be determined, and we&amp;rsquo;ll have an extensive example of how it can be
implemented for go programs and integrated with Github Actions.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Changing Code Empathically</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/2020-05-changing-code-empathically/</link><pubDate>Sun, 17 May 2020 11:40:00 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/2020-05-changing-code-empathically/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One of my core values is empathy. It is also one of the core principles where I work. You can feel the empathy in a lot of our day to day ceremonies, communication, documentation, code, code reviews, and even in our Pull Requests.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is about changing code by optimizing for happiness.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-few-words-on-empathy"&gt;A few words on Empathy&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Empathy" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;Wikipedia defines empathy&lt;/a&gt;
 as being “the capacity to understand or feel what another person is experiencing from within their frame of reference, that is, the capacity to place oneself in another&amp;rsquo;s position”.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Exploring the PROXY Protocol</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/2020-02-exploring-the-proxy-protocol/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Feb 2020 20:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/2020-02-exploring-the-proxy-protocol/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Some time ago, I needed to load balance websocket connections over AWS Elastic Load Balancers (ELB) or Classic Load Balancers as they are now called. But ELBs did not (and still don&amp;rsquo;t) support proxying websocket traffic over their HTTP(S) listener. To support websocket traffic, a TCP listener is required. This means that the proxy server (ELB) looses knowledge of the HTTP protocol since it goes from being a layer 7 (application) proxy to being a layer 4 (transport) proxy. Without knowledge of HTTP, the proxy can&amp;rsquo;t add the &lt;a href="https://developer.mozilla.org/en-US/docs/Web/HTTP/Headers/X-Forwarded-For" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;&lt;code&gt;X-Forwarded-For&lt;/code&gt; HTTP header&lt;/a&gt;
 to let upstream servers know what the original client IP address is.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Project: Aylmer Canine Club Membership Visualization</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/2020-01-project-overview-canine-club/</link><pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2020 12:00:00 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/2020-01-project-overview-canine-club/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently, my dog Bhumie joined our &lt;a href="https://www.clubcaninaylmer.com/" target="_blank" rel="noopener"&gt;local canine club&lt;/a&gt;
. The club protects dog owner rights in our small neighborhood like ensuring the existence and maintenance of our dog parks. Signing up meant that Bhumie&amp;rsquo;s picture would show up on the club&amp;rsquo;s website which made me browse the existing members/dogs. Looking at the different pages is painful. The site navigation was quickly put and added on without thinking about the user experience.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Overthinking of a Door to Door Scam</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/2019-12-overthinking-of-a-door-to-door-scam/</link><pubDate>Sat, 14 Dec 2019 15:37:42 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/2019-12-overthinking-of-a-door-to-door-scam/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Recently we got the visit of a door to door salesperson. We don’t get much of those usually. But this time we did, and it was very different. Curious as we are, we asked tons of questions and ultimately were able to figure that it was a con. For total disclosure, we think it was as we don&amp;rsquo;t have formal proof.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post summarizes how it played out, the research I did on the company, and a bit on the different tactics that were used on us.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Worker process pattern, a story</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/worker-process-pattern-a-story/</link><pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2019 08:27:51 -0400</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/worker-process-pattern-a-story/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This post is just a little funny story to explain why you might need a worker process in your architecture. It roughly follows the Pixar storytelling formula.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are more technical details at the end.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Some golang gotchas</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/some-golang-gotchas/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Apr 2018 02:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/some-golang-gotchas/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Go is such a simple and elegant language. There is no magic happening and reading go code is so straightforward. But like any language there are some gotchas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This post is about some general Golang gotchas (and neat tricks I have used or seen people use).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="range-and-iterators"&gt;Range and iterators&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This gotcha is a pretty important one that I see people do all the time. It is a very tricky one to track down as well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>How I keep up to date</title><link>https://seriousben.com/posts/how-i-keep-up-to-date/</link><pubDate>Mon, 30 Jan 2017 12:19:51 -0500</pubDate><guid>https://seriousben.com/posts/how-i-keep-up-to-date/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Over the years, I have always been searching to learn more. I remember when I discovered HN years ago now. The world just made so much more sense. Out of a sudden, I had a goal, I was excited by so much knowledge, by the potential that software engineering had. I discovered people outside my extended social circle that I wanted to be like. Remote mentors that I never met. It gave me so much motivation to learn and be better.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>